[{"question":"<p><strong>When literature recreates real events, it is said to be __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Didactic","Factual","Fictitious","Allegorical"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When literature teaches moral lessons, it is said to be ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Instructive","Informative","Didactic","Dynamic"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a function of literature.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inciting","Entertaining","Correcting","Exposing"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>As a medium for exposing and correcting ills in the society literature is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Allegorical","Satirical","Political","Abusive"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Literature is referred to as a slice of life when it _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Recounts real event","Entertains its audience","Reveals reality in society","Accuses leaders of insensitiveness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The time of the events in a literary text is referred to as __ setting<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Special","Spatial","Temporary","Temporal"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What distinguishes drama from other literary genres is that it is meant to be _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Read","Acted","Recited","Viewed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The writer of a play text is referred to as ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Playwriter","Playwrite","Playright","Playwright"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major divisions of a novel is called _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chapter","Stanza","Act","Scene"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The perspective from which the story in a novel is narrated is referred to as _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Angle","Focus","Technique","Point of view"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A misuse of a word in place of another one due to similarity in their sounds is known as _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Error","Parallelism","Malapropism","Mistake"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a figure of speech.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Climax","Oxymoron","Antitheses","Mime"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a figure of speech.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Climax","Oxymoron","Antitheses","Mime"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______&nbsp;is an indirect reference to an event, speech or action in the past.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Allusion","Exaggeration","Pun","Innuendo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the poem below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Life is rise and fall<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A tale of comings and goings<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The rhyme scheme of the poem is _______<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Of travails and doings<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>But death ends all<\/strong><\/p>","options":["aabb","aaba","abba","abab"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The central theme of the poem is_____&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hope","Love","Faith","Vanity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The tone of the poem is that of _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Resignation","Anger","Sorrow","Command"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The type of rhyme in lines 2 and 3 is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alternate","Internal","Medial","Couplet"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the extract below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>William Shakespeare: <em>The Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker A: The hou&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; s&nbsp; o&nbsp; come<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The very minute bids thee ope thine ear<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Obey, and be attentive. Canst thou remember<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A time before we came unto this cell?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>I do not think thou canst, for then thou wast not<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Out three years old<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker B: Certainly, Sir, I can!<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Who&nbsp; is&nbsp; speaker&nbsp; A?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Antonio","Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the extract below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>William Shakespeare: <em>The Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker A: The hou&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; s&nbsp; o&nbsp; come<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The very minute bids thee ope thine ear<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Obey, and be attentive. Canst thou remember<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A time before we came unto this cell?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>I do not think thou canst, for then thou wast not<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Out three years old<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker B: Certainly, Sir, I can!<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Who&nbsp; is&nbsp; speaker&nbsp; A?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Antonio","Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Speaker B is _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ariel","Caliban","Andrian","Miranda"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The response of speaker B shows that speaker&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>A<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Underrates her memory","Dislikes her behavior","Understands her feelings","Approves of her carriage"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______<\/strong><strong>is the playwright of <em>Women of Owu<\/em>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Femi Osofisan","Wole Soyinka","Kobina Sekyi","Willam Golding"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major theme in <em>Women of Owu<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hatred","Tolerance","Political bigotry","The folly of war"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In <em>Arms and the Man<\/em> Major Saranoff eventually marries_____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Catherine","Raina","Nicola","Louka"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>______ is the playwright of <em>The Importance of Being Earnest.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oscar Wide","Oscar Wild","Oscar Wilde","Oscar Wade"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_________<\/strong><strong>misplaced Jack Worthing in a leader handbag.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cecily","Gwendolen","Mrs. Prism","Lady Bracknell"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these characters in <em>The Importance of Being Earnest<\/em> is a clergy.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Algemon","Cardew","Brackell","Chasuble"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who is the author of <em>Lord of the Flies<\/em>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Williams Shakespeare","Lord Baron","Williams Golding","Earnest Hemmingway"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A predominant theme in <em>Lord of the Flies<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The innateness of evil","Religious fanaticism","Necessity for social order","The uselessness of adult"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which song is meant to lull a baby to sleep?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ballad","Lullaby","Dirge","Ode"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The last six lines of a patrachan sonnet is called ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Septet","Quatrain","Sextet","Octave"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A quatrain contains __ lines.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Five","Three","Four","Six"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>__&nbsp; is a moment of relief in a tragic play brought about through a comic scene.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><br \/>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tragic relief","Comic relief","Suspense","Comedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>is a device used to bring past event into focus to clarify present events in literature.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prologue","Exposition","Foreshadowing","Flashback"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Question:17 are based on African and non-african poetry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Thepoet-persona in serende\" can be described as s&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["sanguine lover","deceptive suitor","jilted husband","romantic minstrel"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Question:17 are based on African and non-african poetry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Thepoet-persona in serende\" can be described as s&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["sanguine lover","deceptive suitor","jilted husband","romantic minstrel"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>GENERAL LITERARY tcatastrophes called beforehickens PRINCIPLES<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>question: 18 is based on general literary principles&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>the part of a play when the pilot&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["anagnorisis","denouement","epitasis","epilogue"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>question: 19 is based on general literary principles&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong><em>verfremdungeffekt&nbsp;<\/em>is often associated with the plays<\/strong><\/p>","options":["samuel becket","luigi pirandello","jean-baptiste poquelin","performed behind closed door"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Question: 20 is based on general literary principles&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A closet drama isn a play meant to be a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["read rather than performed","read and performed","performed and screened","performed behind close door"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Question: 21is based on general literary principles&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A comic play performed or sokenlu music is called&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["burletta","opera","melodrama","farce"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p>Section E: LITERARY APPRECIATION<\/p>\n<p><strong>Question: 22 is based on based on literary appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>i was born the stroke of wars, i was born by the revages of disease by the event know the stench of this <em>landsipho sepamla the soweto<\/em> i love p<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>the central concern of the excerpt above is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["war","disases","the poets homeland","the plagues of stench"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on general literary principles&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>look at my father he never had a bath in his life and he lived to be ninety-eight the healthiest man in bulgaria\" Benard shaw arms the man p 39<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>from the excerpt above. it can be deducted that&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["the speaker loathes bathing","there is a connection between bath and longevity","Bulgarians out-law bathing","the speaker condemns his father"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>i felt unsafe with scratches of uncertain weather security in the detention camp jared Angira silent voices p. 42&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The mood of the poet&nbsp; persona in the excerpt above is that of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["vertigo","euphoria","coyness","anxiety"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on general literary principles&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A parade of legal robbers the state sponsored assemblyb of terminators of the less priviledge colleagues of the underworld kayode Ariyo \"Licensed robbers p.20 the tone of the excerpt above is that of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["falttery","sarcasm","admiration","despair"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Section A:LITERARY APPRECIATION<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>This question is based on literary appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp;\"For tools<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; no more than books we had and the will to make a noise joe de graft university franchise day<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The tone of the excerpt above is that of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["self-mockery","self-praise","admonition","recrimination"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on literary appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Today i stand in the cloud remembering my good mood on the stage where i once stood waving at the cheering crowed\" olufemi ojediran at your back\" the sound devices in the excerpt above are&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["assonance and rhyme","alliteration and onomatopoeia","repetition and assonance","caesura and rhyme"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on literary appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The moon become jealous that kanta the child of the sun was so much loved by the people of the land\"<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong><em>&nbsp; Okello Oculi Kanta Riti<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The figure of speech in the excerpt above is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["allusion","sarcasm","irony","personfication"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on literary appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Never mind ...my twisted servant...my destiny henceforth shall be in my hands and no longer at the tip of your tongue. only one king at a time&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>&nbsp; Ahmed Yeriman majagbe<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>from the excerpt above the speaker is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["elated","enraged","rude","confused"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on African and non-african peotry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>According to P.O.C umeh in The Ambassadors of Poverty the ambassadors of poverty are the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["riling elite","foreign diplomats","pastoralists","displaced refugees"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based onAfrican and non-african peotry<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Serende is a poem translated into English from&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hausa","Xhosa","Acoli","Swahili"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based onAfrican and non-african peotry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>In langston Hughes Negro speaks of Rivers Eupharates refers to a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["mountain","nation","river","forest"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This section is based on general liberary priciples<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>the juxtaposition of two constrasting ideas in the line of a poam is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["irony","litotes","euphemism","oxymoron"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This section is based on general liberary priciples<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A limerick is made up of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fourteen lines","eight line","five lines","ten lines"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This section is based on general liberary priciples<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The common metrical pattern in a sonnet is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["iambic","spomdee","trochaic","dactylic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This section is based on general liberary priciples<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A orm of entertainment that is market by music, song, dance and elaborate costume called&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["masque","cantata","reggae","jazz"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This section is based on general liberary priciples<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The poetic device in which a part is used to represent in whoile is called&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["metonymy","synecdoche","hyperbole","litotes"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on African and Non-African Poetry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>David Rubadiri in \"An African Thunderstorm\" paints a graphic picture of the thunderstorm through the use of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["simile and personification","irony and imagery","hyperbole and rhyme","innuendo and satire"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Mazisi Kunene is an African poet from&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ghana","Nigeria","Malawi","South Africa"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A novel that has a very strong presence of the supernatural is known as&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fiction","gothic","travel tale","fairy novel"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a tragic-comedy, the unknotting of the plot, the resolution of the mystery and the resolution of mystery and the resolution of the misunderstanding is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["exposition","denouement","catharsis","hubris"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The exclusive right given to authors to protect their works from unlawful production or reproduction is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a copyright","an authority to write","a constitutional provision"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>An epic deals with&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["humor","tragedy","gothic","hero"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The sudden revelation of events as they happen is called<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["epiphany","revelation","relay-events","resonance"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Comic relief is used in a work of art to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["to suspend disbelief","to manoeuvre the portals of narration","to create chiaroscuro","to suspend tension"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>I thank you God for creating me black<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>For making of me<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Porter of all sorrows<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Setting on my head<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>The World.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><strong>The images in this excerpt suggests<\/strong><\/p>","options":["happiness","sorrow","anger","kindness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>I thank you God for creating me black<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>For making of me<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Porter of all sorrows<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Setting on my head<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>The World.<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><strong>The&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">World<\/span> as used above is an example of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["irony","metaphor","exaggeration","parody"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Agosu, if you go tell them,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Tell Nyideu, Kpeti and Kove<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>That they have done us evil;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Tell them their house is falling<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And the trees in the fence<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Have been eaten by termites<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><strong>The general idea in the extract is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["neglect","praise","ridicule","worship"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Blessed Nigerians, Who eat pestilence to sleep&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Blessed the poor,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Who inherit thons...<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><strong>The central motif in this except is <\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["religious","pride","poverty","deceit"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Blessed Nigerians, Who eat pestilence to sleep&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Blessed the poor,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Who inherit thons...<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><strong>The extract is an example of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pun","hyperbole","irony","parody"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>\"Your hand is heavy, Night, upon my brow\" is an example of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["hyperbole","onomatopoeia","apostrophe","oxymoron"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>The human beings who in most admire are those withour sterling qualities but are extraordinary in their ordinariness, the unsung heroes who will never be in the limelight or boulevard of fame, people who do great things when no one is watching or those who are not marked with the maple leaves of chieftaincy titles. They only wear fate, hard work, perseverance, anonymity and time. Yet, they are passionate, caring, visionary, sincere, determined and honest. These qualities mold those that are special without being aware. I strive to stay true to some of these qualities that I admire. To find a person with a few of these qualities is rare these days. To know someone who has all of them is amazing and a true blessing. (Except from Tomorrow Left Us Yesterday -&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><strong>Tayo Olafioye)<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>From this passage, the people that the writer admire are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["poor","brilliant","rich","unassuming"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>The human beings who in most admire are those withour sterling qualities but are extraordinary in their ordinariness, the unsung heroes who will never be in the limelight or boulevard of fame, people who do great things when no one is watching or those who are not marked with the maple leaves of chieftaincy titles. They only wear fate, hard work, perseverance, anonymity and time. Yet, they are passionate, caring, visionary, sincere, determined and honest. These qualities mold those that are special without being aware. I strive to stay true to some of these qualities that I admire. To find a person with a few of these qualities is rare these days. To know someone who has all of them is amazing and a true blessing. (Except from Tomorrow Left Us Yesterday -&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><strong>Tayo Olafioye)<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The writer informs the reader that people with good qualities are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["many","few","fearful","famous"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Star, hide your fires;<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Let not light see my black and deep desires. The eyes winks at the hand; yet let that be which the eye fears, when it is done, to see<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>In these lines, Shakespear uses<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hyperbole","metonumy","simile","onomatopoeia"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>She unpacked the novels she had brought with her, and turned them over. These were the books she had collected over years from the mass that had come her way. She had read each one a dozen times, knowing it by heart, following the familiar tales as a child listens to his mother telling him a well-knnown fairy tale. <\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>This character may be best described as a woman<\/strong><\/p>","options":["of habit","of poor means","of wide literary interest","with poor memory"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When he was turned over, his eyeballs stared upward. In amazement and horror, his mouth was locked open wide: His trousers, soaked with blood, were torn open, and exposed to the cold, white air of morning. The thick hairs of his groin matted together, black and rust-red, and the wound that seemed to be throbbing still... This passage achieves realism through the use of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["details","simple words","the long sentence","the past tense"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Earth has not anything to show more fair Dull would he be of soul who could pass by A sight so touching in its majesty:<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>This city now doth, like garment, wear the Beauty of the morning. It suggested in lines that<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the beauty of the morning gains from the beauty of the city","the beauty of the city gains from the beauty of the morning","the beauty of the city and the beauty of the morning are unrelated","the beauty of the same has nothing to do with either the city or the morning"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on African and Non African Poetry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>David Rubadiri, the author of \"An African Thunderstorm\" hails from&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kenya","Rwanda","Ghana","Malawi"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on African and Non African Poetry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>\"The dominant mood in Soles\" is that of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pleasure amidst pain","doom and despair","regret and optimism","hope and regret resignation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on African and Non African Poetry<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>For rhetorical effect, Mazisi Kunene in \"Heritage of Uberation\" uses&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["rhetorical question","irony","repetiton","assonance"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>\"He already had five wives and was soon going to break the leg of the antelop the sixth time\". The expression \"break the leg of the antelope\" means to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["be on honey moon","offer ritual sacrifice","hunt for antelope","have a new baby"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In China, according to&nbsp;D H Lawrence, bats are symbol of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["death","birth","caution","joy"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The greatest challenge to the poet-personae in Andrew Marvells \"To His Coy Mistress\" is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chariot","love","time","youth"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>This question is based on literary appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>\"But the pigs were so clever that they could think of a way around every difficulty. As for the horses they know every inch of the field and infact understood the business of mowing and raking\", the dominant literary device in the excerpt above is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["repitition","mimesis","ellipsis","personification"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>\"The diary, maids and men had flocked down from their cottages and out of the Dairy-House with the arrival of the cows from the meads; the maids working in patterns not on an account of weather but to keep their shoes above the moulds of the barton\"<\/strong><\/p>","options":["urban","celestial","pastoral","religious"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>\"the animals saw no reason to disbelief him, especially as they could no longer remember very clearly what conditions has been like before the rebellion. All the same were days when they felt they would sooner have had less figures and more food\". The tone of the passage above is quite<\/strong><\/p>","options":["exhilarating","cynical","optimistic","obsequious"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>\"We are tired of waiting for another war. <\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Our trees, their leaves have shed. The winter <\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>has come and gone. Spring flowers have blossom and withered\". <\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>In line two of the poem above, the poet uses<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ellipsis","alliteration","inversion","oxymoron"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>\"I come and go a pilgrim grubbily unkempt stubbornly cheerfully defiantly whistling hope and grumbling for crumbs of success out of all near defeats\" the poet-personae in the poem above is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["resigned to fate","a holy man","a daily traveller","suffering but optimistic"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"}]